Guide to the South Asian Pamphlets Collection, 1920-2005 (bulk 1950-2000) RL.01235
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Pakistan Pamphlets, 1948-2005, bulk 1960s-1990s, 58 boxes
  - Water Resources and Irrigation, 1949-1992, 1 box
    - Research and Development Activities of Drainage and Reclamation Institute of Pakistan. [Islamabad], Drainage and Reclamation Institute of Pakistan, Pakistan: 1992. (Box PA-57)
      Brochure 4. Publication no. 33.
    - Soil Conservation Research and Its Impact on the Agricultural of the Barani Uplands of West Pakistan. Khan, Abdur Rashid and Chaudhry, M. A. Hameed. [Lahore], Department of Agriculture, Pakistan: 1966? (Box PA-57)
    - Some WAPDA Projects at a Glance. Public Relations Division, Wapda. Lahore, Pakistan: 1960? (Box PA-57)
    - Statement on the Water Dispute between West Punjab and East Punjab. Constituent Assembly ( Legislature). Karachi, Governors-General Press and Publishing, Pakistan: 1949. (Box PA-57)
      Statement by Dr. Mahmmud Husain, Deputy Minister for Foreign Affairs and Commonwealth Relations.
    - Tarbela Band - Lahaur: Pani aur Bijli ka Taraqqiyati Idarah. Tarbela Dam. [Tarbela Dam], Pakistan: 1982? (Box PA-57)
  - Women in Pakistan, 1967-1992, 1 box
    The 43 pamphlets in this section discuss women's education and training, violence against women, the status of women in Islam, Muslim Family Law, women in various professions, women in politics, women's health and employment, laws relating to women, and issues concerning prostitution. There is also a pamphlet on Muslim girls in the United States. Includes publications of the Women's Division of the Government of Pakistan, reports from the National Conference of Muslim Women, held in Pakistan, and eleven newsletters published by the All Pakistan Women's Association from 1960-1970.
    - APWA. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA, Pakistan: 196-? (Box PA-58)
      The history of APWA is the story of women of Pakistan.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1967. (Box PA-58)
      April-June 1967.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1967. (Box PA-58)
      July-Sept. 1967.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1967. (Box PA-58)
      Oct-Dec, 1967.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1968. (Box PA-58)
      Jan.-Mar. 1968.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1968. (Box PA-58)
      Apr.-June 1968 and July-Sept. 1968 combined issue.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1968. (Box PA-58)
      Oct.-Dec. 1968.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1969. (Box PA-58)
      January-March 1969.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1969. (Box PA-58)
      April-June 1969.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1969. (Box PA-58)
      July-Sept./Oct.-Dec. 1969.
    - APWA Newsletter. All Pakistan Women's Association. Karachi, APWA Information and Research Bureau, Pakistan: 1970. (Box PA-58)
      Jan.-Mar. 1970 and April-June 1970 and July-Sept. 1970.
    - Battered Housewives in Pakistan. Shamim, Tahira, Mohammad Pervez, Sohail Abbas and Seema Pervez. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1985. (Box PA-58)
    - Changing Status of Women in Islamic Pakistan, The. Helbock, Lucy. [Islamabad], USAID, Pakistan: 1975. (Box PA-58)
    - Data Base on Women in Agriculture and Rural Household. Pakistan. Research Wing. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1984. (Box PA-58)
      F. A. O. Funded Project.
    - Development Planning and Women. Qureshi, M. L. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1983. (Box PA-58)
    - From the Shadows into Light. [n.p.], FPAP, Pakistan: 1972. (Box PA-58)
      Produced for the IPPF on the occasion of The UN Status of Women seminar on Family planning, Istanbul, July 1972.
    - Impact of Employment on Women and Their Families. Hafeez, Sabeeha. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1984. (Box PA-58)
    - Inventory of the Training Programmes for the Dais (TBA) in Pakistan. Pakistan. Women's Division. Islamabad, Pakistan: 1984. (Box PA-58)
    - Muslim Family Laws and Their Implementation in Pakistan. Zia, Shehla, Hina Jilani and Asma Jahangir. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1982. (Box PA-58)
    - Muslim Girls in American Society. Kherie, Altaf Ahmad. Karachi, Holy Quran Society of Pakistan.Pakistan: 19-- (Box PA-58)
    - Muslim Women. Mohammad, Inam. Karachi, [no publisher], Pakistan: 1974? (Box PA-58)
    - National Conference: Role of Women for Effective Participation in Local Government. Islamabad, Government of Pakistan, Pakistan: 1980. (Box PA-58)
      Islamabad, June 18 to 24, 1980.
    - National Conference of Muslim Women: Address by President General Mohammad Zia-ul-Haq. Zia-ul-Haq, Mohammad. Islamabad, Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, Pakistan: 1980. (Box PA-58)
    - Nutrition of Women and Children. Department of Obstetrics & Gynaecology, Jinnah Post-Graduate Medical Centre, Karachi. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1984. (Box PA-58)
    - One Hundred Days in Power, Achievements of People's Government: Welfare of Women. Islamabad, Government of Pakistan, Pakistan: 199? (Box PA-58)
      19th Oct, 1993 to 26th Jan. 1994.
    - Patterns of Female Employment in Mining and Construction Industries. Systems Limited, Lahore. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1983. (Box PA-58)
    - Population Welfare Services. International Conference on Population. [n.p.], All Pakistan Women's Association, Pakistan: 1984. (Box PA-58)
      6-13 August, Mexico 1984.
    - Portrayal of Women in Communication Media. Pakistan Women's Institute, Lahore. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1983. (Box PA-58)
    - Protective Legislation for Factory Women and Mine Workers in Pakistan. Women's Division, Cabinet Secretariat. Islamabad, Research Wing, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1982? (Box PA-58)
      Extracts from various labor laws.
    - Recommendations of the National Conference of Muslim Women. Islamabad, National Conference of Muslim Women, Pakistan: 1980. (Box PA-58)
      17-20 Zilhaj, 1400 - 27-30 October, 1980.
    - Sex Role Images in the Text Books. Anwar, Muhammad. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1982. (Box PA-58)
    - Status of Women in Islam. Islamabad, Pakistan Publications, Pakistan: 19-- (Box PA-58)
    - Studies on Rural Women in N.W.F.P. Pakistan. Government of Pakistan. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1983? (Box PA-58)
      Summaries of various studies conducted from 1980 - 1982.
    - Study of "Abducted" Women in Pakistan, A. Abbas, Sohail, Mohammad Pervez, Tahira Shamim and Seema Pervez. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1985. (Box PA-58)
    - Study of Destitute Women in Pakistan, A. Pervez, Seema, Sohail Abbas, Mohammad Pervez and Tahira Shamim. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1985. (Box PA-58)
    - Study of Prostitutes in Pakistan, A. Abbas, Sohail, Seema Pervez, Tahira Shamim and Mohammad Pervez. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1985. (Box PA-58)
    - Tyranny of Rape, The. Human Rights Commission of Pakistan. Karachi, Pakistan: 1992. (Box PA-58)
      Papers read at a seminar, Karachi, Feb. 20, 1992.
    - UN Women's Development Decade - Its Relevance to Pakistan, The. Khan, Begum Ra'ana Liaquat Ali. [Karachi], [no publisher], Pakistan: 1978. (Box PA-58)
    - Women in Industry: Phase I. Hafeez, Sabeeha. Islamabad, Research Wing, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1983. (Box PA-58)
    - Women in Industry: Phase II: Indepth Study. Hafeez, Sabeeha. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1983. (Box PA-58)
    - Women in Islam. Khuhro, Hamida. Islamabad, Women's Division, Pakistan: 1984. (Box PA-58)
    - Women in Pakistan: A New Era? Khan, Nighat Said. London, Applied Socio Economic Research (ASR), UK: 1988. (Box PA-58)
    - Women's Division. Pakistan. Women's Division. Islamabad, Pakistan: 1983. (Box PA-58)
- Sri Lanka Pamphlets, 1950-1988, 1 box
  The 58 pamphlets in this section were published by official government agencies, private institutes and individuals. Topics areas include Sinhalese language and literature, biographies, ethnic tensions and violence, rural development, religion and philosophy, economic plans, politics and government, trade unions, the Eelam People's Revolutionary Liberation Front, agriculture, religious shrines, archaeology, energy, industry, law and legal education, and dams.
  - Aids to the Study of Sinhala through Phonetics. Wijeratne, David. Sri Lanka: Colombo, [The Author], 1988? (Box SR-1)
    For beginners, especially foreigners.
  - Authentic Biographical History of Mudaliyar Don Adrian Wijesinghe Jayewardene, the Self-Made Man, An. Abeyesinghe, J. Dias. Sri Lanka: Nawala, Douglas D. Ranasinghe, 1969. (Box SR-1)
  - Barricades at the Temple. Fontgalland, Guy de.Sri Lanka: [n.p.], [The Author], 196-? (Box SR-1)
  - Bridges for Villages. Somanader, Kenneth J. Sri Lanka: [n.p.], Information Department Publication, 196-? (Box SR-1)
  - Buddhism and Science: Collected Essays. Buddhist Publication Society. Sri Lanka: Kandy, 1967. (Box SR-1)
    The Wheel, Publication No. 3; with the essays of K. N. Jayatilleke, Robert F. Spencer and Wu Shu.
  - Colombo Plan, The. Colombo Plan Bureau. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1971. (Box SR-1)
    No. 2 Aid Contributions.
  - Colombo Plan in Action, The. Colombo Plan Bureau. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1971. (Box SR-1)
    No. 1 Introductory (Revised).
  - Contemporary Sinhala Literary Scene, The. Amarasekera, Gunadasa. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1969. (Box SR-1)
  - Crisis in Sri Lanka, The. Amarasekera, Anil. Sri Lanka: Colombo, [The Author], 1975. (Box SR-1)
  - Dagobas of Ceylon. Buddhist Publication Society. Sri Lanka: Kandy, 1967. (Box SR-1)
  - Dawn of the Mahaweli Era, The. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Irrigation, Power & Highways. Sri Lanka: [n.p.], 1976. (Box SR-1)
  - Dear Sri Lanka Ambassador…Your Slip is Showing! Tamil Information Centre. UK: Surrey, 19--? (Box SR-1)
  - Economic & Political Trends in Contemporary Ceylon. Amerasinghe, H. S. India: New Delhi, India International Centre, 1966? (Box SR-1)
    Gist of a talk delivered at India International Centre on June 18, 1966.
  - Employee's Councils in Sri Lanka: A Review of Two Years of Operation. Kuruppu, D. B. Sri Lanka: Colombo, The Nation, 197-? (Box SR-1)
  - EPRLF in Eelam Liberation Struggle… Eelam People's Revolutionary Liberation Front. India: Madras, 198-? (Box SR-1)
  - Forty Years of Socialism. Keuneman, Pieter. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Peoples' Publishing House, 195-? (Box SR-1)
    A note left in the pamphlet reads "picked up 1958".
  - Gal Oya Project and the Crisis of Agriculture, The. Wickremasinghe, S. A. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Peoples' Publishing House, 1951. (Box SR-1)
  - Good Structure in Nursery Soil Mixtures. Tolhurst, J. A. H. Sri Lanka: Talawakelle, The Tea Research Institute of Ceylon, 1966. (Box SR-1)
    Advisory Pamphlet No.7/66.
  - Government Policy on Private Foreign Investment. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Planning and Economic Affairs. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1968. (Box SR-1)
  - Greeks and Romans: An English Sinhala Reader. Silva, L. W. de. Sri Lanka: Colombo, The Colombo Apothecaries' Co., Ltd., 1968. (Box SR-1)
  - Guide to Polonnaruva. Paranavitana, S. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Government Press, 1950. (Box SR-1)
  - Guide to Sigiriya. Devendra, D. T. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Government Press, 1951. (Box SR-1)
  - Guide to the Ratnapura National Museum. Sri Lanka. Department of National Museums. Sri Lanka: [n.p.], 1967. (Box SR-1)
  - H-Bomb War: A Report to the British Nation. The Peace Movement. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Tribune Publications, 1966. (Box SR-1)
  - Hundred Villages Development Scheme, A: 1967 - 71. The Lanka Jatika Saravodaya Shramadana Sangamaya. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1970. (Box SR-1)
  - In Search of Refuge: A Brief Case Study of Sri Lanka Tamil Refugees. Baskar, J. Paul. India: Dindigul, Peace Trust, 1985. (Box SR-1)
  - Islandwide One Rupee Fund. Sri Lanka. National Development Organisation, Ministry of Social Services, and the Ministry of Rehabilitation. USA: Arlington, VA, 1986. (Box SR-1)
  - Journal on International Development. Sri Lanka: [n.p.], 1986. (Box SR-1)
    Circulated in the United States, Tokyo, Seoul (Korea), United Kingdom and Sri-Lanka.
  - Kataragama Mosque and Shrine. Hassan, M. C. A. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Al Haj S. A. M. Thauoos, 1968. (Box SR-1)
  - Let Us Produce More Food. Government of Sri Lanka. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], 196-? (Box SR-2)
  - Mahaweli. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Land, Irrigation & Power. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 197-? (Box SR-2)
  - Milk Condensary, Polonnaruwa, Saves Rupees 23 Million Annually, The. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Agriculture & Food. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], 196-? (Box SR-2)
  - More Power to the People: Facts About the Proposals to Set Up District Councils. Government of Sri Lanka. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], 1968. (Box SR-2)
  - Motor Map of Ceylon. Sri Lanka. Survey Department. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], 1966. (Box SR-2)
  - New Industrial Policy, A. Subasinghe, T. B. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], [Ministry of Industries and Scientific Affairs], 1970. (Box SR-2)
  - One-man Rule Over the People: Statement of the United Left Front. United Left Front. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], M. Austin Perera, 197-? (Box SR-2)
  - Power for Progress. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Land, Irrigation & Power. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1968. (Box SR-2)
  - Psychological Aspect of Buddhism, The. Thera, Piyadassi. Sri Lanka: Kandy, Buddhist Publication Society, 1972. (Box SR-2)
  - Reinsurance and "The Rupee Drain". Mendis, Stanley. Sri Lanka: Colombo, [The Author], 1967. (Box SR-2)
  - Report on Cultivation Habits and Practices in Toruwe Tulana N. C. P. Sri Lanka. Water Resources Board. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1968. (Box SR-2)
  - Resource Development. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Lands & Land Development. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1980. (Box SR-2)
  - Rules. Sri Lanka. Council of Legal Education. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1970. (Box SR-2)
  - Second Annual Report. Sri Lanka. The Law Commission. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 1980. (Box SR-2)
    August 1979 to July 1980.
  - Simon Casie Chitty. Wijeyeratne, Nissanka. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Law & Society Trust Lecture Series Inaugural Lecture, 1984. (Box SR-2)
  - Sinhala Youth Cautions Sri Lanka Government. Perera, Jehan. India: Madras, Tamil Information Centre, 1984. (Box SR-2)
    The article in this booklet appeared in the Saturday Review, Sri Lanka, Vol. 3, No. 13, on 12th May 1984.
  - Some Comments on the Education Bill. Jayasuriya, J. E. Sri Lanka: Kandy, [The Author], 1967. (Box SR-2)
  - Special Leases Scheme: What It Is, How It Works, Its Benefits. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Land, Irrigation & Power. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], 196-? (Box SR-2)
  - Sri Lanka: July 1983 Violence Against "Indian Tamils". Sivanayagam, S., ed. Sri Lanka: Madras, Tamil Information Centre, 198-? (Box SR-2)
    A brief case study of anti-Tamil violence at Badulla, Nuwara Eliya and other plantation areas.
  - Sri Lanka: Where the State Is at War With Tamils. Tamil Eelam Information Unit. Sri Lanka: Madras, 1983. (Box SR-2)
  - Sri Lanka's Minority Problem. All India Congress Committee (I). India: New Delhi, 19--? (Box SR-2)
  - Tame the Mahaveli, To. Sri Lanka. Ministry of Land, Irrigation & Power. Sri Lanka: Colombo, 19--? (Box SR-2)
  - Temple Entry Movement in the North. All Ceylon Saiva (Hindu) Practices and Observances Protection Society. Sri Lanka: [n.p.], 1968. (Box SR-2)
  - Thattumaru' and 'Kattimaru' Systems of Rotation of Cultivation of Paddy Land: A Case Study in the Village of Unduruwa Halmillawewa, Anuradhapura District. Ganewatte, P. Sri Lanka: Colombo, Agrarian Research & Training Institute, 1974. (Box SR-2)
  - "Whither Jaffna": An Essay. Nagaratnam, R. Sri Lanka: Colombo, [The Author], 1969. (Box SR-2)
  - Why I Became a Buddhist? Wijesekera, C. A., ed. Sri Lanka: Maharagama, [The Author], 1970. (Box SR-2)
    A lecture delivered by the late Mr. A. E. Buultjens B. A. (Cantab) in 1899.
  - Young Lanka. Government of Sri Lanka. Sri Lanka: [Colombo], The Government Press, 196-? (Box SR-2)
    Agricultural Corps: Its Objectives & How It Functions.
  - Zionism - Welcome to Sri Lanka. Ajantha, B. A. Sri Lanka: Madras, Tamil Information Centre, 1984. (Box SR-2)